<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Sri Sadhan</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Task type classification of Human-robot collaboration using EMG signals.</title>
      <link>/project/emg_classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/emg_classification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This projects concentrates on classifying the type of task being performed by the human in collaboration with a admittance controlled robot. Any physical task can be categorized as Fine, Gross or Fine-Gross based on the required human motor skills. By detecting the type of task being performed, the parameters (admittance control gains) of the robot can be tuned to improve the quality of interaction. Here, the Electromyography (EMG) signals recorded from the Myo armband attached to the human arm are used for the classification of task in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Control of a Variable Stiffness Mechanism for the Hammering Task</title>
      <link>/project/hammering/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/hammering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Variable stiffness actuators can be used in a variety of robotics applications for dynamic manipulation tasks such as hammering a nail or flipping a burger. Here, a semi-active variable stiffness mechanism is used for enhancing the dynamic manipulation of a stiff robot. The mechanism is attached to the end-effector of a robot and its performance is investigated over a hammering task. The hammering task is posed as an optimal control problem to maximize the velocity of the hammer-head while hitting the nail. The problem is solved to obtain an optimal end-effector trajectory of the robot and the desired mechanism stiffness as a function of time. The performance of the mechanism is then tested for three different stiffness settings on the obtained trajectory. Through experiments, we show that the mechanism can achieve higher velocities in the variable stiffness setting when compared to the stiff actuation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variable Stiffness Gripper</title>
      <link>/project/gripper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/gripper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: All the above images on this page are shot by &lt;strong&gt;Douglas Levere&lt;/strong&gt; and are the property of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.acsu.buffalo.edu/~ehsanesf/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Human in the Loop Systems lab&lt;/a&gt;, University at Buffalo. Please refer to this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.buffalo.edu/ubnow/stories/2019/09/esfahani-robotic-gripper.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/files/spaghetti-stick.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D real-time pose detection of objects</title>
      <link>/project/object_tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/object_tracking/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
